Employed Wangfu Dean and our
王府学部長と当社の採用
Please, vice presidents, ladies up front.
副大統領の皆様、どうぞ。
and our Dean Wu
そして私たちのディーン・ウー
Dear colleagues, fellow students
親愛なる同僚、学生の皆様
Good morning everybody
みなさんおはようございます
Good morning
おはよう
Today is after I take office
今日は就任後です
Organized academic lectures for the first time
初めて学術講演会を開催
Very happy to organize this
これを企画できてとても嬉しいです
about us
私たちに関しては
An academic lecture by the former principal
前校長による学術講演会
The former headmaster is something we admire very much.
元校長は私たちがとても尊敬している人です。
a principal
校長
Because he was in the 40th to 59th years of the Republic of China
中華民国40年から59年くらいの人だから。
Served as principal for 19 years
19年間校長を務めた
The fifth principal of Zhiwen School
志文学校第5代校長
He is overall in the administration of our school
彼は私たちの学校の管理全般に携わっています
done a lot of work
たくさんの仕事をした
Especially the administrative system of our whole school
特に学校全体の管理システム
and recruitment
そして採用
On the other hand
一方で
Thematic planning and cooperation with outside property rights
テーマ別企画と外部財産権との連携
established a very complete system
非常に完全なシステムを確立しました
Even the work of the China Merchants Association
中国招商協会の取り組みも
He built it
彼がそれを建てた
Therefore, the 19-year principal has contributed a lot to the school
したがって、19年間校長を務めた彼は学校に多大な貢献をしてきました。
I am careful, everyone has seen it in my newspaper
私は気をつけています、誰もが私の新聞でそれを見ました
People say I've been doing administrative work for a long time
私は長い間事務の仕事をしていると言われます
From the director to the dean to the current principal
理事長から学部長、そして現校長へ
In fact, I haven't been doing it for 19 years
実は19年間もやってなかった
I did it for 17.5 years
17.5年間やりました
So your ex-principal also played music
あなたの元校長も音楽を演奏していたんですね
Especially after I was elected as the principal
特に校長に選ばれてからは
Start to keep in mind the school rules
学校のルールを意識し始める
Only then did I know that being the principal
そのとき初めて、私は校長であることを知りました
The president of National Taiwan University is also very lenient
国立台湾大学の学長も非常に寛大です
So we can appreciate that the former headmaster
したがって、私たちは元校長のことを高く評価することができます。
It's not easy, of course, the 19-year-old president of National Taiwan University
もちろん、それは簡単ではない、国立台湾大学の19歳の学長
Because NTU itself is a representative of Taiwan
NTU自体が台湾の代表だから
So not just administrative work in schools
学校の事務作業だけではありません
in the overall political system
政治システム全体の中で
Response to government Response to international
政府への対応 国際的対応
due to our old loss
私たちの昔の喪失のせいで
It's a very, very difficult job
それはとてもとても難しい仕事です
so i'm really happy today
だから今日は本当に幸せです
I will host
私が主催します
We invite the principal to give a lecture
校長先生をお招きして講演会を開催します
Then we will do it with you today
じゃあ今日は一緒にやろう
It is our Zheng Yue'e who gave the speech
スピーチをしたのは私たちの鄭岳娥です
Our Academician Zheng
私たちのアカデミー会員、鄭
He is also our chair professor at National Taiwan University.
彼は国立台湾大学の主任教授でもあります。
I am very interested in the topic he talked about
彼が話した話題にとても興味があります
Because he talked about the evolution of Chinese characters
彼は漢字の進化について話したので
Academician Zheng Academician Zheng I'm sorry
鄭学者 鄭学者 ごめんなさい
sorry so he himself
ごめんなさい、だから彼自身です
I think Academician Zheng's voice is
鄭学者の声はこうだと思います。
I don't need to talk
話す必要はない
everyone knows everyone
誰もがみんなを知っている
he is mainly in this
彼は主にこれにいます
Combining Five Points of Literature
文学の5つのポイントを組み合わせる
Western literature
西洋文学
I think he's a very good example of a domain
彼はドメインの非常に良い例だと思います
In particular, he put the western space
特に彼は西洋の空間を配置しました。
or body
または体
Combined with Five Points Literature
ファイブポイント文献との組み合わせ
What he said today has something to do with this
彼が今日言ったことはこれと関係がある
Just look at the evolution of our Chinese characters
漢字の進化を見てください
I think today's speech is also very exciting
今日のスピーチもとても刺激的だと思います
really happy today
今日は本当に幸せだった
especially when we passed a year
特に一年を過ぎたとき
It was very cold during the Chinese New Year ahead
旧正月を控えてとても寒かったです
Today looks sunny
今日は晴れそうです
I'm sure I heard a very wonderful story today
今日はとても素晴らしい話を聞けたと思います
once again i thank you all for your attendance
ご参加いただきました皆様に改めて感謝申し上げます
I also wish you all a healthy, safe and happy new year
また、皆様が健康、安全、そして良い新年を迎えられますようお祈り申し上げます
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
This is what our central government posted about configuration considerations.
これは、中央政府が構成に関する考慮事項について投稿したものです。
In fact I don't need to rely on this thinking
実際のところ、この考えに頼る必要はありません
I'm for this
私はこれに賛成です
to former dean
元学部長へ
Our former dean is very respectful
私たちの元学部長はとても尊敬しています
all admire him
皆が彼を賞賛する
In fact former principal
実は元校長
former principal
前校長
our dean
私たちの学部長
Both have served very long in both academic institutions
二人とも両方の学術機関で非常に長い間勤務してきました
13 years in Central
セントラルで13年
Is by far the longest serving dean
学部長としてはこれまでのところ最も長く勤務している
So he has a lot of buildings
それで彼はたくさんの建物を持っています
during his tenure
彼の在職中
Five research institutes were established
5つの研究機関を設立
information center
インフォメーションセンター
I don't care
私は気にしない
To prepare another five
あと5つ用意する
Places like this human center
このヒューマンセンターに似た場所
So for the center to lay the next one
だからセンターが次のものを敷くために
very solid foundation
非常に強固な基盤
That's why we continue to carry forward his contribution today
だからこそ私たちは今日も彼の貢献を引き継いでいきます
Central physicians should have the scale of today
中央医師は今日の規模を持つべきである
I don’t want to talk about being in National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学にいたことについては話したくない
He has countless talents
彼には数え切れないほどの才能がある
Therefore, many teachers and students of National Taiwan University are very grateful to him.
したがって、国立台湾大学の多くの教師や学生は彼に非常に感謝しています。
Lecture by the Dean of the Former Faculty Principal
元学部長講演会
As for the Central Research Institute and National Taiwan University
中央研究所と国立台湾大学について
Today we specially invited
今日は特別にご招待させていただきました
Special Professor of the Chinese Department of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学中国語学科特別教授
Academician of Justice
正義の学者
He is also an amalgamated professor at our Central Research Institute of Philosophy
私たち中央哲学研究所の併合教授でもあります。
His achievements in comparative literature
比較文学における彼の業績
It is obvious to all in the International College
インターナショナルカレッジでは誰にとっても明らかです
I'm also very close to him personally.
私は個人的にも彼と非常に親しいです。
I think we'll just leave the rest of the day to the Justice Fellows
今日の残りはジャスティスフェローに任せようと思います
come sing his academic
彼の学問を歌いに来てください
I wish my heartfelt love and share it with everyone
私の心からの愛を祈り、それをみんなと共有します
Thank you all, happy new year and good work
皆様、ありがとうございます、新年明けましておめでとうございます、お疲れ様でした
President Chen Vice President Huang of Central Hospital
陳院長 中央病院の黄副院長
Today's keynote speaker, Academician Zheng
本日の基調講演者、鄭学術院士
Dear teachers, students, distinguished guests
親愛なる先生方、生徒の皆様、ご来賓の皆様
Good morning everybody
みなさんおはようございます
good
良い
It's a great honor to be here today
今日ここに来られてとても光栄です
Academic lectures in memory of the late father
亡き父を偲んで学術講演会を開催
This year is the 43rd and 39th
今年は43回目で39回目
Thirty-ninth time
第三十九次
For forty years since my father passed away
父が亡くなってから40年間
I think today's lecture has two characteristics
今日の講義には2つの特徴があると思います
The first feature we at National Taiwan University are very happy about
国立台湾大学がとても喜んでいる機能の第一弾
And we have a very good new principal
そしてとても優秀な新しい校長が来ました
President Chen Wenwen
陳文章校長
We would like to take this opportunity to express to him
私たちはこの機会に彼にこのことを伝えたいと思います
Gong Hyuk means
コンヒョクの意味は、
I also hope that National Taiwan University will be under his leadership
また、国立台湾大学が彼のリーダーシップの下に置かれることを願っています。
To be able to come here to go one step further
ここに来てさらに一歩進められるように
The second is today's chief general
二人目は今日の総大将
Academician Zheng
鄭学者
The topic he spoke was very definite
彼が話したテーマは非常に明確だった
Just now the headmaster said no
今校長はノーと言った
But as far as my personal memory
ただ、私の個人的な記憶としては、
Because the last 34 years
なぜなら、この34年間、
america back
アメリカに戻る
every year i attend
毎年参加しています
past 11 years
過去11年間
Every lecture is a natural science
すべての講義は自然科学です
and biological sciences
と生物科学
It's hard today
今日は大変です
Come to a Humanities and Social Sciences Come to
人文社会系に来てください
And to find such a wonderful speaker
そしてこんな素晴らしいスピーカーに出会うなんて
So I think today's lecture
ということで今日の講義は
we can expect
期待できます
Today is the eleventh day of the first lunar month
今日は旧暦の最初の月の11日です
remember
覚えて
the eleventh day of the first lunar month of a certain year
ある年の陰暦最初の月の11日
haven't burnt yet
まだ燃えていない
So I still have the opportunity to say goodbye to everyone here
だから、ここにいるみんなに別れを告げる機会はまだ残っている
I wish you all good luck in the new year
新年のご多幸をお祈り申し上げます
happy family, good health, good luck
幸せな家族、健康、幸運
Thanks
ありがとう
former dean
前院長
Then Dean Huang Hu
それからディーン・ファン・フー
And our patriarch, Principal Chen
そして私たちの家長であるチェン校長
Good morning, my friends
おはよう、私の友人
really honored today
今日は本当に光栄です
Can serve as Mr. Si Liang, the former principal of Gu
区の元校長である思良氏を務めることができる
115th Memorial Academic Lecture
第115回記念学術講演会
In fact, in 2007, I personally
実際、2007 年に私は個人的に
Also met the former dean at Yale University
イェール大学の元学部長とも会った
I really admire his demeanor and eloquence.
私は彼の態度と雄弁さを本当に尊敬します。
So today we can actually meet
それで今日は実際にお会いできるんです
I'm glad too
私も嬉しいよ
About the topic I want to talk to you today
今日話したいテーマについて
Actually the main
実はメインの
I want to share a bit of my own research experience
私自身の研究経験を少し共有したいと思います
it was at the beginning of the twentieth century
それは20世紀初頭のことでした
Some Thoughts on the Transformation of Chinese Characters or Chinese
漢字または中国語の変形に関するいくつかの考え
So in particular, I will focus on the issue of heterosexuality
そこで、特に異性愛の問題に焦点を当てます。
What about this question?
この質問についてはどうでしょうか？
I think we'll go back to language
言語の話に戻ろうかと思います
The underlying assumption that is often referred to
よく言及される根本的な仮定
For example, if pragmatism prevails in the
たとえば、現実主義が主流になっているとします。
We will ask what is the use of language
言語の使用について尋ねます
When you ask what is the use of language
言語の使用とは何ですかと尋ねると、
Two basic assumptions emerge
2 つの基本的な仮定が明らかになります
The first is that language is a tool
1つ目は、言語はツールであるということです
When you use language as a tool
言語を道具として使うとき
we imagine
私たちは想像します
That could be, say, a truck carrying goods
それは、たとえば、商品を運ぶトラックかもしれません
So as long as he can carry
だから彼が運べる限り
any car will do
どの車でもいいでしょう
It seems that each session itself is not so important
各セッション自体はそれほど重要ではないようです
because he is just a tool
彼はただの道具だから
the second will involve
2番目は次のことを含みます
The second imagination is language
2番目の想像力は言語です
probably just neutral transparent
おそらくただの無色透明
like looking through a glass window
ガラス窓から覗いているような
Because don't we see through it at a glance?
だって一目見たらわかるじゃないですか。
So in fact, this pregnant or existing
つまり、実際には、この妊娠中または既存の
or the idea of ​​neutral transparency
または中立的な透明性の考え方
In fact, it affects our daily life
実は私たちの日常生活にも影響を及ぼしているのです
a lot of thinking and judgment
たくさんの思考と判断
therefore
したがって
If you think that the original text is just a tool for communication
原文を単なるコミュニケーションツールと考えている場合
is neutral and transparent
中立的で透明です
but you in your daily life
でも、日常生活の中であなたは
obviously often heard
明らかによく聞かれる
why don't you understand my feelings
なぜ私の気持ちを理解してくれないのですか
so why don't you understand
それでなぜ理解できないのですか
these things are not
これらのものはそうではありません
Just treat the original text as a tool
元のテキストをツールとして扱うだけです
it can be solved
それは解決できます
So I thought I'd take that angle today
なので今日はその角度から撮ってみようと思いました
the one everyone knows
誰もが知っている人
Thoughts about the original text
原文についての感想
to go
持ち帰り
Then in the early twentieth century
それから20世紀初頭には
Chinese characters
漢字漢語
Transformation especially in China
特に中国における変革
make an example to illustrate
説明するために例を作る
for example
例えば
Everyone knows the second two yellow butterflies
2番目の2匹の黄色い蝶は誰もが知っています
written by Hu Shi
胡思著
Also considered the first heart poem in the vernacular
この言語での最初の心の詩とも考えられています。
what do you know about butterflies
蝶について何を知っていますか
In these two contexts of classical and modern
古典と現代という二つの文脈の中で
it's not just a butterfly at all
それは決してただの蝶ではありません
For example, the first one is familiar to everyone
たとえば、最初のものは誰もが知っています
Learner Zhuangzhou dreams of being a butterfly
学習者の荘州さんは蝶になることを夢見ています
It is the story of Zhuangzhou Dream Butterfly
荘州夢蝶の物語です
look at the end
最後を見てください
I don't know everyone knows that Meng is a butterfly fish
孟がチョウチョウウオであることを誰もが知っているわけではありません
Butterfly is a dream for Zhou Yu
蝶は周瑜の夢です
You know this punctuation mark is a posterity
この句読点が後世に残されたものであることはご存知でしょう
It turned out there wasn't
無いことが判明した
How does it break the sentence?
どのように文が壊れるのでしょうか？
it uses virtual characters
仮想キャラクターを使用します
For example, wild, fish, fish, etc.
たとえば、野生、魚、魚などです。
it uses these to make sentences
これらを使って文を作ります
so you can find butterflies here
ここで蝶を見つけることができます
Of course not just butterflies
もちろん蝶だけではありません
because it actually says
実際にそう言ってるから
between people and things
人と物との間
I can communicate with each other
お互いにコミュニケーションが取れる
But in this butterfly poem by Hu Shi
しかし胡思のこの蝶の詩では
It obviously really wants to talk about why the two butterflies
明らかに本当に話したいのは、なぜ二匹の蝶がいるのかということです。
Because the poem was written when it was in New York
なぜなら、その詩はニューヨークにいたときに書かれたものだからです。
It's different from when I was studying in college
大学時代とは違う
the apartment facing it
それに面したアパート
Facing the Hudson River
ハドソン川に面している
it sees two butterflies
二匹の蝶が見える
fly around
飛び回る
Are these two butterflies
この二匹は蝶ですか？
number of two
2の数
and causally
そして因果的に
because how so how
なぜなら、どうやって、どうやって
This perfectly echoes
これは完璧に響きます
Hu Shi himself is very particular about
胡施自身が非常にこだわっているのは、
In fact, language expression
実は言語表現というのは、
can only be precise
正確にしかできない
and must be precise
そして正確でなければなりません
Therefore, there must be a specified symbol
したがって、指定されたシンボルが存在する必要があります
have grammar
文法がある
to be obvious
明らかであること
and meaning
そして意味
to be sure
念のため
Here we can find
ここで見つけることができます
Actually the word butterfly
実は蝶という言葉は
in different uses
さまざまな用途で
polymorphism
多態性
Originally heterosexual
本來多異性
In traditional Chinese characters
繁体字で書くと
no problem
問題ない
but from now on
でもこれからは
there is a problem
問題があります
Why
なぜ
Let's look at a lot of the background of the year
今年の背景をいろいろ見てみましょう
in 1933
1933年に
I found a popular science unique
ポピュラーサイエンスのユニークな発見
Science Pictorial
科学図鑑
science pictorial is
科学図鑑は
Science founded by the Chinese
中国人が創始した科学
Confederate Sole
南軍ソール
Inside the science pictorial
科学絵画の内部
One of them is called
そのうちの1人はこう呼ばれます
where for example
たとえばここで
treat the human body as a machine
人間の体を機械として扱う
The brain is the general management office
そして脳は総合管理局
The mouth is the mouth is the entrance for the fuel
口は口です、燃​​料の入り口です
And the nose is like the fragrance blowing
そして鼻は香りが漂っているようなものです
In this mechanical view
この機械的な視点では
It has something to do with the entire machine civilization.
それは機械文明全体に関係がある
Also 1930s
こちらも1930年代
Louis Monford
ルイ・モンフォード
Inside Technics and Civilization
技術と文明の内部
The most famous is the classification of space-time
最も有名なのは時空の分類です。
He said time can be used in minutes
彼は時間は分単位で使えると言った
seconds, days, years, etc.
秒、日、年など。
plan a computational
計算を計画する
independent events
独立したイベント
This is no longer the experience of the event
これはもうイベントの経験ではありません
For example, we often say
たとえば、私たちはよく言います
That evening when the gorge was full of sky
峡谷が空で満たされたあの夜
no you tell me now
いいえ、今教えてください
what time am i now
私は今何時ですか
it's totally different
それは全く違います
perception of time
時間の認識
And another example is the space
もう一つの例は宇宙です
no longer through the relationship of things
もはや物事の関係性を通してではなく
figuratively symbolic or religious sanctity
比喩的に象徴的な、または宗教的な神聖さ
let's talk about space
宇宙について話しましょう
For example, the most famous
たとえば、最も有名なのは、
Perspective to talk about space
宇宙を語る視点
If we talk about space from perspective
宇宙を視点から語るなら
It is the same as anything that is familiar with everyday religious values
それは日常の宗教的価値観に馴染みのあるものと同じです
Actually it doesn't matter
実際にはそれは関係ありません
every time i'm flying
私が飛んでいるたびに
I like to see its route map the most
路線図を見るのが一番好きです
Then you'll find out that
そうすれば分かるでしょう
Oh, this is how Jinweidu drew it
ああ、これはジンウェイドゥが描いたものです
Oh so we are here now
ああ、それで私たちは今ここにいるのです
wait to get there
そこに着くまで待ってください
You will find that this is an event composed of spacers and lines
これはスペーサーとラインで構成されたイベントであることがわかります。
Here is a chart of the golden scale
これが黄金スケールのチャートです
Indeed, people pass through this partition line
確かに人はこの境界線を通過する
Conquered or rediscovered the universe
宇宙を征服または再発見した
But should we be careful
でも気をつけるべきか
Conversely, people accept that these squares and lines
逆に、人々はこれらの四角形と線を受け入れます
arrangement and arrangement
アレンジメントとアレンジメント
This is when polygamy becomes a problem
一夫多妻制が問題になるのはこのときだ
Obviously in 1911
明らかに1911年に
General Encyclopedia Xingda Dictionary published by Huang Ren
一般百科事典『興達辞典』黄仁発行
can be seen inside
中が見える
General Encyclopedia Xingda Dictionary
一般百科事典興達辞典
It is also a very important reference book for us
私たちにとってもとても大切な参考書です
but it's very cooked
しかし、それは非常に調理されています
There is only one left in Taiwan, there should be only two or three left in the world
台湾には1台しか残っていない、世界には2、3台しか残っていないはずだ
Then this one is now hidden in the National Library of Taichung
そして、これは現在、台中の国立図書館に隠されています
In this general encyclopedia new dictionary
この総合百科事典の新しい辞書には
It mainly explains all new disciplines
主にすべての新しい分野について説明します
So it's called a discipline, like a discipline manual
だからそれは規律と呼ばれる、規律マニュアルのようなもの
For example, psychology, literature, gold studies, etc.
たとえば、心理学、文学、金学などです。
that's interesting
それは面白い
It specifically says in the preface
序文に具体的に書いてある
Leishu in traditional Chinese
繁体字中国語のレイシュ
These are too hesitant and vague, we don't want them
これらはあまりにもためらいすぎて曖昧です。私たちはそれらを望んでいません。
at this point in time
この時点で
Definition and ambiguity become differences that must be chosen
定義と曖昧さは選択しなければならない差異となる
You'll find it categorized and numbered by stroke
ストロークごとに分類され、番号が付けられています。
Sort by number of strokes
画数順に並べ替える
In classifying this mainstream
この主流を分類すると
Originally the mainstream of the development of Western natural history
もともと西洋博物学発展の主流
Then under this classification
次に、このカテゴリーの下に
we have to be careful what it might lose
私たちはそれが何を失うかに注意しなければなりません
For example, it may lose its overall structure
たとえば、全体的な構造が失われる可能性があります。
I give one
1つあげます
one example
一例
In the whole ordinary Hundred Stars Big Magnetic Spot
普通の百星全体の大きな磁気スポットで
There is no star magnetic stripe
スター磁気ストライプはありません
that he put us through the stars might think
彼が私たちを星空に連れて行ってくれたのだと思うかもしれない
feeling, feeling
感じ、感じ
It's all in psychology
それはすべて心理学にあります
And specifically
そして具体的には
through natural science
自然科学を通して
to understand feelings or feelings
感情や感覚を理解する
But when we use star in Chinese
しかし、中国語でスターを使うときは、
what he might be involved in
彼が何に関わっているのか
I'll just name a few
いくつか挙げてみます
The star may be related to the star system
この星は星系に関係している可能性があります
Xing may be related to Wen Xing
シンはウェンシンと関係がある可能性があります
Because we know writers are stars of literature
作家が文学のスターであることを私たちは知っているからです
when you speak and write
話したり書いたりするとき
In fact, it is expressed through text
実はそれは文字で表現されているのです
That's why we call Wenxing
だからこそウェンシンと呼ぶのです
Then in science
それから科学では
We know there is also astrology
占星術もあることは知っています
But when the magnetic stripe of the star is removed
でも星の磁気ストライプが外されると
This series of connections is gone.
この一連のつながりはなくなりました。
you can't see at all
まったく見えない
Also in 1915
1915年にも
Hu Shi is a man who sees the extreme
胡施は極限を見る男だ
What about after he went to America to study?
彼がアメリカに留学した後はどうですか？
Because he wants to teach Chinese characters
漢字を教えたいから
then he said
それから彼は言いました
we should have grammar
私たちは文法を持っているべきです
Otherwise it is very difficult to teach
そうでなければ教えるのは非常に困難です
So the previous sentence
ということで、前の文は
to specify to be obvious
明白であるように指定する
It is not easy to determine
判断するのは簡単ではありません
It is from this experience of teaching foreign languages
外国語を教えていたこの経験から
So we can find from this data that
したがって、このデータから次のことがわかります。
He mainly focuses on foreign language teaching
主に外国語教育に注力している
with Chinese education
中国語教育を受けた
In fact, there should be a difference
実際には違いがあるはずです
This is what I just said
これは私が今言ったことです
There are a group of people like Hu Mingfu in China
中国には胡明福のようなグループがいる
or Ren Shuyong
レン・シュヨンとか
In order to emulate him, he was influenced by the American Science magazine
彼を見習うために、彼はアメリカのサイエンス誌に影響を受けました。
Therefore, Science magazine was also established in China.
それで中国でも科学科学雑誌を創刊しました
in this magazine
この雑誌で
Hu Shi's article on punctuation marks
句読点に関する胡石の記事
Published in January 1916
1916年1月発行
That is what he wrote in 1915
それは彼が1915年に書いたものです
Then this article is called "On Sentence Fighting and Character Symbols"
それでは今回の記事は「文章格闘と文字記号について」です。
What he's talking about is actually the punctuation we use today.
彼が話しているのは、実は今日私たちが使っている句読点のことです。
You can find this issue inside the drug tomb
この問題は麻薬の墓の中で見つけることができます
let's say algebra
代数としましょう
Then this scientific spirit talks about machine skin eggs and so on
そして、この科学的精神は機械の皮の卵などについて話します。
It's very very scientific and mechanical
それはとても科学的で機械的なものです
or a technical magazine
または技術雑誌
What about the characters and symbols of Hu Shi's drama dramas?
胡適のドラマの登場人物やシンボルはどうなっているのでしょうか？
It's actually a small part of all his ideas.
実際、それは彼のアイデア全体のほんの一部に過ぎません。
Of course it is also an important part
もちろんそれも重要な部分です
He once said that if you sort out old books,
彼はかつて、古い本を整理するとこう言いました。
Be sure to segment and punctuate
必ず区切って句読点を入れてください
And it should be written like a mind
そしてそれは心のように書かれるべきです
get together
集まる
Then one by one
それから一つ一つ
What about this view?
この見方はどうでしょうか？
In fact, Hu Shi is a sword fighter
実は胡思は剣士だ
Like I said he's very, very passionate to push a lot of things
先ほども言ったように、彼は多くのことを推進することに非常に情熱を持っています
So we can find
それで私たちは見つけることができます
In 1916, he published On Judou Ji Character Symbols
1916年、彼は『柔道地の文字記号について』を出版した。
I just said that
私はちょうどそれを言いました
Then successively
それでは引き続き
Especially in 1920
特に1920年には
Many people let the Ministry of Education announce the implementation of mind punctuation
多くの人が文科省にマインド句読点の導入を発表させています
Then Tongling National Primary School Grade 12
その後銅陵国立小学校12年生
To change the language style of the national language
国語の言語スタイルを変更するには
Abolish ancient Chinese
廢除古文
And finally more importantly
そして最後にもっと重要なことは
He finished a very long article
彼は非常に長い記事を書き終えた
two or three articles
2つまたは3つの記事
finally published together
ついに一緒に出版されました
On the Reform of Guoyu Grammar
国宇文法の改革について
Since then, he has promoted the vernacular movement
それ以来、彼はヴァナキュラー運動を推進してきました。
to a more hierarchical
より階層的なものに
and
と
implemented through government measures
政府の施策により実施される
So if we're talking about a literary revolution now
それで、今私たちが文学革命について話しているとしたら、
We can't actually ignore
実際には無視することはできません
Take the forty or fifty years from 1970 to 1920
1970 年から 1920 年までの 40 年か 50 年を考えてみましょう
On the one hand, there is a world revolution that adds new words and new themes
一方で、新しい言葉や新しいテーマを加えた世界革命が起こる
But more importantly, emphasize
しかし、もっと重要なことは、強調してください
We have a literary revolution in grammar and punctuation
私たちは文法と句読点において文学革命を起こしています
And if you go back to the source
そしてソースに戻ると
It is related to the technological civilization of a certain technological system
ある技術体系の技術文明に関わるもの
A Value Framework Based on Scientific Machines
科学的機械に基づく価値フレームワーク
he compared to the traditional
彼は伝統的なものと比較した
re-established the modern method of reading composition
現代的な作文の読み方を再確立した
Also opened Chinese
中国語もオープンしました
and a new page in psychological self-reflection
そして心理的内省における新たなページ
often we hear
よく私たちは聞きます
Literary Controversy Literal Controversy
文学論争 文字通り論争
But in fact, these four words are too simplified
しかし実際には、これらの 4 つの単語はあまりにも単純化されています
why
なぜ
Because we actually missed a lot of thinking and discussion in the middle
なぜなら、途中で多くの考えや議論を見逃してしまったからです。
let's say the first
最初に言いましょう
What I'm talking about is based on these few items
私が話していることはこれらのいくつかの項目に基づいています
Let's say the first grammar
最初の文法を言ってみましょう
We feel we didn't spell a word
私たちは一言も綴っていなかったと感じます
At that time, a group of people felt that this was our shame.
当時、ある人々はこれが私たちの恥だと感じていました。
So we should look to English grammar
だから私たちは英語の文法に目を向けるべきです
we need grammar
文法が必要です
But there are no Chinese characters in English grammar
しかし、英語の文法には漢字はありません
How will it continue to develop in the future
今後どのように発展していくのか
This is the question that people continued to think about at that time
これは当時人々が考え続けた問いです
What if there is no English grammar, Chinese characters?
英語の文法や漢字がなかったらどうなるでしょうか？
second rhetorical
第二の修辞
you might ask
あなたは尋ねるかもしれません
Well, if grammar is so important, with English grammar
文法がそんなに重要なら、英語の文法で
why do we need rhetoric
なぜレトリックが必要なのか
Why were there so many fake grammar names back then
なぜ当時は偽の文法名がこれほど多かったのか
Some Discussions about Rhetorical Words
修辞的な言葉に関するいくつかの議論
Well, if you have Wen French
さて、ウェン・フレンチをお持ちなら
Why do we still have the so-called semantics of rhetoric
なぜ私たちはレトリックのいわゆる意味論をまだ持っているのでしょうか
Hope to develop into a discipline
学問として発展していきたいと考えています
Why is there still semantics?
なぜまだセマンティクスが存在するのでしょうか?
because they want to ask how meaning comes about
彼らは意味がどのようにして生まれるのかを尋ねたいからです
This is of course related to the most fundamental problem of language
もちろんこれは言語の最も根本的な問題に関係しています
Finally, I will talk about the issues of polygamy and modernity.
最後に、一夫多妻制と近代の問題についてお話します。
Okay, first point about grammar
さて、最初のポイントは文法についてです
At that time, of course, the first book about Chinese characters
もちろん当時、初めての漢字に関する本
It is Wentong, it mainly uses classical Chinese
Wentongです、主に古典中国語を使用します
But the first grammar book on the national language was
しかし、国語に関する最初の文法書は
Li Jingxi's New Mandarin Grammar
李静熙の新しい中国語文法
published in 1924
1924年に出版
After publication, it caused a lot of discussion
公開後、大きな話題を呼びました
In 1942, Liao Shuqian made a summary
1942 年、廖淑謙は次のようにまとめました。
in the process
過程の中で
There are at least two key points in the discussion of Chinese grammar
中国語文法の議論には少なくとも 2 つの重要なポイントがあります
The first point is
最初のポイントは
when we talk about Chinese grammar
中国語の文法について話すとき
It is true that it is not necessary and impossible to imitate the West
確かに西洋を模倣する必要はなく、また不可能です。
He didn't say no need
彼は必要がないとは言いませんでした
No need to imitate Xifa
シファを真似する必要はない
we must break
私たちは壊さなければなりません
Limitations between polytheory or word theory
多理論と単語理論の間の限界
For example, what is word theory
たとえば、単語理論とは何ですか
Are you singular or plural
あなたは単数ですか、それとも複数ですか
Are you present tense or ongoing tense
現在形ですか、それとも進行形ですか
Then Jufa is presiding over verbs, numerals, etc.
次に、ジュファは動詞、数字などを主宰します。
it is we going to break this
これを壊すのは我々だ
Pay attention to English grammar
英文法に注意する
Chinese grammar has such a recognition
中国語の文法にはそのような認識がある
In fact, we only need to talk
実際、私たちは話すだけで十分です
think for example
たとえば考えてみる
Airframe, Maodian, Moon, Man-Machine, Banqiao, Frost
機体、毛店、月、人機、板橋、フロスト
This is completely inconsistent with the giant law of Western English
これは西英語の巨大な法則と完全に矛盾しています
Withered vines, mice, faint cliffs
枯れた蔓、ネズミ、かすかな崖
it doesn't fit at all
まったく合わない
But in China it is a sentence
しかし、中国ではそれは文です
Another second point
もう一つの2点目
Lee Kyung Hee expressed it in a convex solution
イ・ギョンヒはそれを凸解で表現した
Jufa should be divided into various parts and functions
Jufaはさまざまな部分と機能に分割する必要があります
what is his mission
彼の使命は何ですか
This is a theoretical sequence
これは理論上の順序です
However, many discussions at that time put forward this
しかし、当時の多くの議論はこれを提案しました
there is a breach
違反があります
where is the order of literature
文学の順番はどこですか
What is a concrete representation of the image
イメージを具体的に表現するとどうなるか
Sentences with thoughts and emotions of things
物事の考えや感情を含む文章
That is the lively element in the article
それがこの記事の生き生きとした要素です
This reminds us of Li Qingzhao's
これを見ると李青照氏の作品を思い出します。
This search for secrets is in a cold mood
この秘密の探求は冷たい雰囲気です
seven seven miserable seven seven
七七 慘慘七七
you will find out
あなたは分かるでしょう
It's totally ungrammatical
ここはまったく文法的ではありません
But these seven sets of spy characters at the beginning
しかし、冒頭のこの7組のスパイキャラクターは、
the pain of ruining his family
彼の家族を破滅させる痛み
push to the top
一気に最高点まで押し上げる
Therefore, traditional calligraphy
したがって、伝統的な書道は、
Everyone knows Mr. Yang Mude
誰もが知っているヤン・ムデ氏
Mr. Chen Shixiang thinks
陳世祥氏はこう考える。
This is the most winged moment
これが最も翼のある瞬間です
When you speak out these seven sets of spy sentences
これらの 7 つのスパイ文を話すとき
so from here
だからここから
It makes sense to reflect on these two points
この2点を考慮するとわかりやすいです
These two reflections are accompanied by
これら 2 つの反射には、
late nineteenth century to early twentieth century
19世紀後半から20世紀初頭
Some phenomena of rhetoric discussed in the name of grammar
文法の名の下に議論されるレトリックのいくつかの現象
often someone will say
たいてい誰かが言うだろう
i know rhetoric
私はレトリックを知っています
it was 1932
1932年のことでした
Is Mr. Chen Wangdao's rhetoric extraordinary?
陳王島氏のレトリックは並外れたものなのでしょうか？
But I want to emphasize here
しかし、ここで強調したいのは
It's not just about the founding of a discipline
それは学問分野の創設だけではありません
In fact, if we compare grammar with rhetoric
実際、文法をレトリックと比較すると、
You know that rhetoric has a purpose
レトリックには目的があることを知っていますか
and most importantly
最も重要な
The first point
最初のポイント
When Grammars Don't Talk About Categories of Meaning
文法が意味のカテゴリーについて語らないとき
When making words and plots related to it
それに関連した言葉やプロットを作るとき
So who is going to talk about the complex relationship between self-containment and meaning?
それでは、自己完結性と意味の複雑な関係について誰が語るのでしょうか?
rhetoric
レトリック
Second point
2点目
When Grammar Becomes a Measure of Parts of Speech
文法が品詞の尺度になるとき
Or when the play structure of the active soldier
または現役兵士のプレイ構成の場合
Who comes outside the standard form of this expression
この表現の標準形式から外れるのは誰ですか
Reconsider Chinese or Chinese
中国語または中国語を再考してください
The Rhetoric of Diverse Possibilities in Emotional Expression
感情表現における多様な可能性のレトリック
so i remember we were in college
だから私たちが大学にいたことを覚えています
The Department of National Taiwan University seems to have no rhetoric
国立台湾大学の学部にはレトリックがないようだ
But I know there are many teachers
でも先生がたくさんいるのは知っています
made important contributions to rhetoric
レトリックに重要な貢献をした
then i felt
それから私は感じました
In fact, we need a new view on rhetoric
実際、私たちはレトリックについて新しい見方を必要としている
If from late Qing Dynasty to early Ming Dynasty
清末から明初期の場合
Corresponding to Western English Grammar
西洋英語の文法に対応
when it strikes
それが襲ったとき
The rhetoric of how we respond
私たちがどのように対応するかのレトリック
had its important place in that century electricity
その世紀において電気は重要な位置を占めていました
What is the Grammar of Change
変化の文法とは何ですか
Can Grammar Be Changed?
文法は変えられるのか？
Here we will see a book
ここで本を見ます
Very important is Tang Yue's rhetorical revolution in 1923
非常に重要なのは、1923 年の唐越の修辞革命です。
Everyone sees that this is 1923
誰もがこれが 1923 年であることを認識します
Earlier than Chen Wangdao's rhetoric was published in 1932
陳王島のレトリックが出版された 1932 年よりも前
Tangyue is not someone else
タンユエは別人ではない
She is a good friend of Hu Shi at Cornell University
彼女はコーネル大学の胡詩の良き友人です
Youth witnesses how she started
若者は彼女がどのように始まったかを目撃します
Her vernacular or literary revolution
彼女の言語革命または文学革命
The three words of psychology we are talking about now
私たちが今話している心理学の3つの言葉
Tangyue too
湯岳も
It was his translation that made the final decision
最終決定を下したのは彼の翻訳でした
He later really became a very important psychologist
彼は後に非常に重要な心理学者になりました
But he is this Hu family, whether it is the piano-pushing literary revolution
しかし、彼はこの胡一家であり、ピアノを弾く文学革命であろうとも
or sorting out the history of the country
あるいはその国の歴史を整理すること
very important partner
とても大切なパートナー
Then he has a book called Xiuci
それから彼はXiuciという本を持っています
grammar of change
変化の文法
The so-called grammar of change is
いわゆる変化の文法は
unusual everyday tone
異常な日常のトーン
He said that in rhetoric or composition
彼はレトリックや作文でこう言った
Using the original text is not just a matter of conforming to grammatical guidelines
原文を使用するということは、文法ガイドラインに従うだけではありません
He says it's just the cognitive function of understanding communication
彼は、それはコミュニケーションを理解するための認知機能にすぎないと言いました
But there is a more important role
しかし、もっと重要な役割があります
is to elicit an emotional effect
感情的な効果を引き出すことです
In particular, he gives a lot of examples that are all about metaphors
特に比喩に関する例をたくさん挙げています。
The example of this metaphor is very interesting
この比喩の例は非常に興味深いです
is what we use now
私たちが今使っているものです
like one of his hearts
彼の心の一つのように
but why say
しかしなぜ言うのか
his square heart
彼の四角い心
Fangfang is the way of dividing squares
方方とは正方形の分割方法です
Fang is often used to describe a woman's admiration or inner state of mind
「牙」は女性の賞賛や内面の精神状態を表すのによく使われます。
Why say a square star
なぜ四角い星と言うのか
It's better not to say one star
星一つは言わない方が良いですよ
Did you notice an important difference between
重要な違いに気づきましたか?
He turned the metaphor into a metaphor
彼は比喩を比喩に変えた
it was just a metaphor
それは単なる比喩でした
square star is a metaphor
四角い星は比喩です
But he became a metaphor
でも彼は比喩になってしまった
We often say Fang Xing
私たちはよく「方興」と言います。
or be speechless
あるいは無言になる
tell the truth
本当のことを言え
The truth is that you have broken your trust
真実は、あなたが信頼を裏切ったということです
why tell the truth
なぜ真実を言うのか
In fact, it is only a metaphor or a metaphor
実際には、それは単なる比喩または比喩にすぎません
Now it's a metaphor
もうそれは比喩です
not to mention
言うまでもなく
For example, anthropomorphic
たとえば、擬人化
wind blowing and falling
風が吹いて落ちる
Blow is our exit
打撃は我々の出口だ
blow the breath out of your mouth
口から息を吹き出す
In addition, descending is from a place where the mountain is relatively high.
なお、下山は比較的山が高い場所からとなります。
to a lower place
低いところへ
This is an anthropomorphic metaphor
これは擬人化された比喩です
But now we also say
しかし今、私たちはこうも言います
the wind is blowing
風が吹いている
In addition, you can also use nature to talk about people
さらに、自然を使って人々について話すこともできます
For example we often say
たとえば、私たちはよく言います
the person's thoughts or thoughts
その人の考えや考え
very profound
非常に奥深い
The depth originally refers to the depth of the water
深さとは本来水の深さを指します。
That distance was originally a telescope for talking about the road
その距離はもともと道について語るための望遠鏡だった
But we use natural phenomena to talk about human beings.
しかし、私たちは人間について語るのに自然現象を使います。
so what about these metaphors
では、これらの比喩はどうでしょうか
It's almost become intentional
ほぼ意図的になってる
let's say you want to think deeply
深く考えたいとしましょう
pondering itself
それ自体を熟考する
is a metaphor to become
になることの比喩です
Situations where everyday spoken English can be used
日常会話の英語が使える場面
This is probably what he said
おそらくこれが彼が言ったことです
inside the grammar of change
変化の文法の内側で
There are many examples that we still use today
今日でも使用されている例がたくさんあります
If we look at the grammar of change
変化の文法を見てみると
Then the part of speech in the grammar
次に、文法上の品詞
really only marks a part of things
実際には物事の一部をマークするだけです
Let's say we define the word as an adjective
この単語を形容詞として定義するとします。
Then he can only express the nature
そうすれば彼は自然を表現することしかできない
This word is the progressive tense
この単語は進行形です
he said action
彼は行動を言った
This is only part of the representation
これは表現の一部にすぎません
But we clearly found
しかし、私たちは明らかに見つけました
so much deep understanding
とても深い理解
The situation of multiple variants of one yin or multiple variants of one word
1 つの陰音の複数の異体字、または 1 つの単語の複数の異体字の状況
these kinds of
こういった種類の
Between sound and concept, between shape and meaning
音とコンセプトの間、形と意味の間
You will find that there is not only one correspondence
対応するものは 1 つだけではないことがわかります
definitely not just a correspondence
決して単なる通信ではありません
If this is the case
このような場合は
In fact, it has already exceeded the norms of parts of speech.
実際、すでに品詞の基準を超えています。
So the linguist Zhang Shilu at that time
それで、当時の言語学者の張実魯は、
He also translated some of Gao Benhan's Chinese works
彼はまた、ガオ・ベンハンの中国語の著作のいくつかを翻訳しました。
he just said pointing
彼はただ指差しながら言った
The word finger turned out to be your toe
指という言葉はあなたのつま先であることが判明しました
That is, he turned out to be a hieroglyph, toe
つまり、彼は象形文字であることが判明しました、つま先
He said what does the word toe conjure up?
彼は、「つま先という言葉から何を連想するでしょうか？」と言いました。
Toe-up, toe-in, middle toe, toe, etc.
トウアップ、トーイン、ミドルトウ、トウなど。
What does this mean about the toes?
これらは足の指について何を意味するのでしょうか？
There is no way to only see the word toe
つま先という単語だけを見る方法はありません
It can be judged by determining the role of its part of speech in the play
劇中の品詞の役割を判断することで判断できる
You have to deliberate and identify from the context
文脈から慎重に特定する必要がある
That is to say, in the process of writing Chinese or interpreting Chinese,
つまり、中国語を書く、あるいは中国語を通訳する過程で、
Aware of the diversity of Chinese
中国人の多様性を知る
thus presenting Chinese or Chinese
したがって、中国語または中国語をレンダリングします
Maximum possibility in heterogeneous expression
異種発現の可能性を最大限に高める
It is why people at that time had to think hard, Jin Si, deep thinking
だからこそ、当時の人々は一生懸命考えなければならなかったのです、ジンシ、深く考えました
very important topic
非常に重要なトピック
Then we will progress to our heterology
その後、異質論に進みます
you may find it strange
奇妙に思うかもしれない
rhetoric is a science
レトリックは科学です
But why did they promote the so-called heterodoxism at that time?
しかし、なぜ当時彼らはいわゆる異端主義を推進したのでしょうか?
This was also in 1933
これも1933年のことでした
Different and Different Studies is a book written by Li Anzhai
『異異学』は李安寨が書いた本です。
In a moment I'll explain why he wrote the book
彼がなぜこの本を書いたのかについてはすぐに説明します
he talked about
彼は話しました
We must pay at least a few percent attention to the application of language and characters
言語と文字の適用には少なくとも数パーセントの注意を払わなければなりません
First, grammar or logic is currently being promoted enthusiastically
まず、現在、文法や論理が熱心に進められています。
But he actually paid little attention to the relationship between language and thought.
しかし実際には、彼は言語と思考の関係にはほとんど注意を払っていませんでした。
At the same time, he pays little attention to the relationship between language and external things.
同時に、彼は言語と外部のものとの関係にはほとんど注意を払っていません。
in graph theory
グラフ理論では
What's more, he doesn't care
さらに、彼は注意を払わない
what readers and listeners say about language
読者とリスナーが言語について何を言っているか
what kind of attitude
どのような態度ですか
I think the last point is very important
最後の点は非常に重要だと思います
I think right now we're working on a lot
今、私たちはたくさんのことに取り組んでいると思います
Whether it is the study of psychology or linguistics
心理学でも言語学でも
neuroscience research
神経科学の研究
Or even the AI ​​artificial intelligence we're driving now
あるいは私たちが今運転しているAI人工知能さえも
this is actually very very important
それは実際にはとてもとても重要です
It is also a very hard part
とても難しい部分でもあります
This last point actually tells us that
この最後の点は実際に次のことを示しています。
our psychology
私たちの心理
all the process
すべてのプロセス
Whether it's emotions, thoughts, emotions, etc.
それが感情、思考、感情などです。
will not be all under the control of symbols
すべてがシンボルの制御下にあるわけではありません
we just have to think
私たちはただ考えなければなりません
Even we often say that the meaning is beyond words
意味は言葉を超えていると私たちでもよく言います
So it's not just the grammar that doesn't regulate our
つまり、私たちの言語を規定していないのは文法だけではありません。
even many words can not express
どんなに言葉を尽くしても言い表せない
So what about meaning generation?
では、意味の生成についてはどうなのでしょうか？
Li Anzhai wrote Semantics
Li Anzhai はセマンティクスを執筆しました
this is very important
これはとても重要です
Then Li Anzhai was affected by the responsibility
その後、李安寨は責任を感じた
In fact, it was influenced by I.A. Richer
実際、I.A. リチャーの影響を受けています。
this person is not someone else
この人は他の人ではありません
He was actually considered to be one of the ten groups of New Criticism
彼は実際、新批評の 10 グループの 1 つと考えられていました。
Then he once gave lectures in China from 1929 to 1931
その後、1929年から1931年まで中国で講演したことがある。
He has a very very famous article
彼には非常に有名な記事があります
It's called Minnin of meaning
意味のミンニンといいます
This one looks weird
これは奇妙に見えます
In fact, he directly
実は彼は直接、
The word Minnin
ミニンという言葉
He analyzed at least 16 meanings
彼は少なくとも16の意味を分析した
That is to say, the word Minnin is not only available to you by looking it up in the dictionary.
つまり、「民人」という言葉は、辞書で調べればすぐにわかるわけではありません。
He speaks the word Minnin
彼はミニンという言葉を話します
For example, his station in the system is the most important
たとえば、システム内での彼のステーションは最も重要です。
We say he has point
彼の言うことは一理あると我々は言う
he has meaning
彼には意味がある
Or it is related to our future expectations
またはそれは私たちの将来の期待に関連しています
we say he makes sense
私たちは彼は理にかなっていると言う
or affirmation of my past efforts
または私の過去の努力の肯定
Or I imagine my acceptance first
あるいは、自分が受け入れられることを最初に想像してしまう
my audience
私の聴衆
The part he wants to know the most
彼が一番知りたい部分
i think he makes sense
彼は理にかなっていると思う
So in this article he is
したがって、この記事では彼は
He actually put forward a very important theory
彼は実際に非常に重要な理論を提唱しました
it's about context
それは文脈の問題です
Theory about context
コンテキストに関する理論
in this article
記事上で
He talks about grammar
彼は文法について話します
often just sees itself as a normative system
多くの場合、自分自身を規範的なシステムとしてしか見ていない
Analyze the so-called correct usage
分析所謂正確的用法
He said that this is actually a matter of minor details.
これは実際には些細な問題であると彼は言いました。
he gave an example
彼は例を挙げた
He said that a French scholar
彼はフランスの学者がこう言いました。
Brunaut
ブルーノート
Already shouted in 1903
1903年にはすでに叫んでいた
part of speech
品詞
That is, the teaching or research method of distinguishing verb names, etc.
つまり、動詞名などの区別に関する教育または研究方法です。
There is a very interesting sentence
とても興味深い一文があります
He said we must make up our minds
彼は私たちが決心をしなければならないと言った
thought-based
思考に基づいた
rather than the study of linguistics based on signs
記号に基づいた言語学の研究ではなく
Then what about I.A. Richards
ではI.A.リチャーズはどうでしょうか？
He actually published a book in the 1930s
彼は実際に1930年代に本を出版しました
Called Science and Poetry
科学と詩と呼ばれる
a very important book
とても大切な本
He later used this book as a basis
彼は後にこの本を基礎として使用しました
published another
別のものを出版しました
The Definitive Edition is Poetry and Sciences
決定版は詩と科学
in this book
この本の中で
two languages
彼は二つの言語を分けた
He said that there is a scientific language
彼は科学言語があると言いました
is the language of science
科学の言語です
the language of pure science
純粋な科学の言語
I hope he is not affected by personal emotions
彼が個人的な感情に左右されないことを祈ります
There is also no need to consider the subject referred to by the symbol
また、シンボルが指す主題を考慮する必要もありません。
Can the music listener be restored?
音楽リスナーを復元できますか?
sensory perception
感覚的知覚
he said it doesn't need
彼はそれは必要ないと言った
But if it's summoning language
でもそれが召喚言語なら
This was in the 1930s
これは 1930 年代のことでした
translate it into emotional language
それを感情的な言語に翻訳する
For comparison with science
科学との比較のために
But I think it might be better to summon
でも召喚したほうがいいかもね
in the calling language
呼び出し言語で
but through the rhythm rhyme
でもリズム韻を通して
and past rhymes experience
そして過去の韻の経験
For example, you read a lot of ancient poems
たとえば、あなたは古代の詩をたくさん読んでいます
You immediately know where to break the sentence with these seven characters
これらの 7 文字を使用すると、文をどこで区切るかがすぐにわかります。
etc.
等
In the memory of the situation
文脈の中で
emotion born of association
つながりから生まれる感情
then calls out on the reader
それから読者に呼びかけます
emotional longing feeling
感情的な憧れの感情
or an attitude
または態度
He said we should have two languages
彼は私たちは2つの言語を持つべきだと言いました
not just one language
1つの言語だけではなく
He did not deny the language of the preceding science
彼は先行する科学の言葉を否定しなかった
But he thinks there should be two languages
しかし彼は 2 つの言語があるべきだと考えています
So if we find that from China
それで、もしそれが中国からのものだとわかったら、
Heard the development of rhetoric from grammar to semantics
文法から意味論へのレトリックの発展を聞く
Reachers' point of view is actually very important to pay attention to
リーチ者の視点は実際に注目すべき非常に重要です
First, he clearly pointed out the grammar
まず、彼は文法を明確に指摘しました
not the main way to understand semantics
セマンティクスを理解するための主要な方法ではない
is a way
方法です
but not the main way
しかし、主要な方法ではありません
Instead, close reading of the text
代わりに、テキストをよく読んでください。
to replace standard grammar teaching
標準的な文法教育を置き換える
the second
二番目
say or write
言うか書くか
In fact, their psychological structure is very complex.
実際、彼らの心理構造は非常に複雑です。
In this ambiguous and contextual poetic language
この曖昧で状況に応じた詩的な言語で
Only then can we be able to distinguish the differences in the expression of poetic and scientific language
そうして初めて、詩的言語と科学的言語の表現の違いを区別できるようになります。
he said the poet
彼は詩人は言いました
Often we have a poem in our hearts
私たちは心の中に詩を持っていることがよくあります
will return to the reciprocating protagonist
往復主人公に戻ります
several years
数年
The playwright is deeply moved by people's affection
劇作家は人間の感情に深く感動する
will have such an important role
とても重要な役割を持つことになる
because he first used the movement and sound of his own words
なぜなら彼は初めて自分自身の言葉の動きと音を使ったからです。
to pique our interest
私たちの興味をそそるために
What is the movement and sound of Zici?
Ziciの動きと音は何ですか？
We can say that the main thing is actually
実際に重要なことは次のとおりであると言えます。
structure and rhythm
構造とリズム
how did he get together
彼はどうやって付き合ったのか
Why is this word put in front
なぜこの言葉が前に来るのか
Why is that word put at the back?
なぜその言葉が後ろに置かれているのでしょうか？
etc.
等
It's what piques our interest
それが私たちの興味をそそるものです
And what about this deep emotion?
そして、この深い感情はどうでしょうか？
It is indeed a science of logic
それはまさに論理の科学です
factors to be ruled out
除外される要素
Ritchard immediately communicated with the alien
リチャードはすぐに宇宙人と交信した
Discuss differences in language use in poetic science
詩学における言語使用の違いについて議論する
Obviously since 1920
明らかに1920年以来
What about the trend of discussing Mandarin grammar?
中国語の文法を議論する傾向についてはどうですか?
There are some discrepancies
多少の誤差はございます
because he turned
彼は向きを変えたから
Meaningful expression based on meaning or emotion
意味や感情に基づく意味のある表現
What is the significance of this in the whole zeitgeist
これは時代精神全体の中でどのような意味を持つのでしょうか
Grammar
文法
beyond standard discourse
標準的な議論を超えた
reveals the development of another Chinese language
別の中国語の発展を明らかにする
mind language
心の言語
Of course, in the end we talked about how to modernize
もちろん、最終的にはどのように近代化するかについて話し合いました。
How to be modern is not the only direction I just talked about
いかにモダンであるかが、先ほど話した唯一の方向性ではありません
On the Modernization Project of Chinese Characters Since the Literary Revolution
文革以来の漢字の近代化事業について
has many angles
多くの角度があります
For example, we want to pinyinize
たとえば、ピンイン化したいとします。
Acousticization
搭聽化
we want to simplify
簡素化したい
Even if we abolish Chinese characters
漢字を廃止しても
Let Chinese characters combine with civilization and science
漢字を文明や科学と結びつける
There are many differences in the location of these calligraphy
これらのカリグラフィーの位置には多くの違いがあります
Perhaps the most famous example is Lin Yutang's Bright Typewriter
おそらく最も有名な例は、Lin Yutang の Bright Typewriter です。
It's very clear and fast
とても明確で速いです
In this Chinese character typewriter
この漢字タイプライターでは
He is a part through romanization and strokes
彼はローマ字表記とストロークによる一部です
The part of the stroke is not the hand, the hand is meaningful
ストロークの部分は手ではない、手に意味がある
The parts of this stroke don't necessarily make sense
このストロークの各部分は必ずしも意味があるわけではありません
he
他
The method used is the number let's say
使用されるメソッドは数値です。
Mr. Wang Yunwu's four-corner number
王雲武さんの四隅の数字
He used this number to further modify the four-corner number
彼はこの数値を使用して、四隅の数値をさらに修正しました。
He said that a word only needs four numbers
彼は単語に必要な数字は 4 つだけだと言いました
These four numbers are not in stroke order
これら 4 つの数字は書き順ではありません
is the stroke that starts with the two tallest ones on the upper left
左上の 2 つの最も高いものから始まるストロークです
with the two strokes on the lower right
右下の2つのストロークで
to form four numbers
4つの数字を作る
then on the ice cube typewriter
それからアイスキューブタイプライターの上で
Lay the parts up
パーツを並べていきます
so you type
それであなたは入力します
In fact, it is combined with mechanized stroke configuration
実際には、機械化されたストローク構成と組み合わせられています。
Professor of Golden Animals at Yale University
イェール大学ゴールデンアニマル教授
He once had a book about Lin Yutang's typewriter
彼はかつて林宇棠のタイプライターについての本を持っていた
He said that this is the meaning system of Chinese characters
これが漢字の意味体系であると彼は言いました
system of conversions to letters
文字への変換システム
is the Western alphabet system
は西洋のアルファベット体系です
This is a very interesting study
これは非常に興味深い研究です
It also tells us that Chinese characters have the possibility of diverse development
また、漢字には多様な発展の可能性があることがわかります。
But this development is worth thinking about here
しかし、この展開はここで考える価値があります
If Chinese characters are pinyinized or symbolized
漢字がピンイン化または記号化されている場合
That is to say, Chinese characters are like Western letters.
つまり、漢字は西洋の文字に似ています。
It can be constructed and spelled out the speaking voice arbitrarily
話し声の綴りと読み上げを任意に構築可能
But there is no way to spell it out
でもそれを言い表す方法はない
with font, meaning
フォント付き、意味
so that speaking organisms connect
話す生物がつながるように
what's the problem
どうしたの
That is, it ignores the basic nature of Chinese culture
つまり、中国文化の基本的な性質を無視しているのです。
When I construct such a set of Chinese
このような中国語のセットを構築するとき
what is my lust
私の欲望は何ですか
is a person with complex perception
複雑な認識を持つ人です
Instead of the pinyin system for the convenience of quick and simple communication
迅速かつ簡単なコミュニケーションの便宜のため、ピンイン システムの代わりに
In fact, through a person with complex perception
実際、複雑な認識を持つ人を通して
to construct a Chinese system
中国のシステムを構築する
become the essence of culture
文化の本質となる
In fact, the question of modernity
実際、近代性の問題は、
We most often think of Fockeau's word thing
私たちはフォッコーの言葉についてよく考えます。
He said that since the 17th century
彼は17世紀以来こう言った
We often record, classify, configure
私たちは頻繁に記録、分類、設定を行います
constructed horizon
構築された地平線
Then this field of view
するとこの視界が
it's called the order of the modern sight
それは現代の視覚の秩序と呼ばれています
what does this contain
これには何が入っていますか
this contains a lot
これにはたくさん含まれています
Museums we frequent
よく行く美術館
natural history we see
私たちが見ている自然史
The financial analysis report we look at
私たちが調べた財務分析レポート
The libraries we looked at Department stores
デパートで見た図書館
and what we talked about today
そして今日話した内容
Grammar and Disciplinary Institutions for Knowledge and Language
知識と言語のための文法および規律機関
These establishments are classified into
これらの施設は次のように分類されます。
juxtaposed or cut in a field of view
視野内で並列またはカット
This is the modern line of sight, the underground line of sight
これが現代の視線、アンダーグラウンドの視線
but
しかし
did you find out
分かりましたか
This is the existence of knowledge prior to man
これは人類以前の知識の存在です
The construction of this knowledge system
この知識体系の構築
prehuman existence
人間以前の存在
it manipulates our look
それは私たちの見た目を操作します
what we see what we think
私たちが見ているもの 私たちが考えていること
feel
所感受
So dominate people
だから人を支配する
So human knowledge
つまり人間の知識
Hawko even said very pessimistically
ホーコは非常に悲観的にさえ言った
This is an inhuman study of the humanities
これは非人道的な人文科学の研究です
inhuman is possible
非人道的な可能性もある
The essence or nature of non-official people
非公務員の本質または本質
here
ここ
The last sentence of the book of words
言葉の本の最後の一文
it is a little mournful in nature to say
これを言うのは少し悲しいことです
people will be erased
人は消されるだろう
like a face in the sand by the sea
海辺の砂の中の顔のように
He said there is no way
彼は方法がないと言いました
exist in the essence and nature of man
人間の本質と性質の中に存在する
If we have been using the framework of modern vision
もし私たちが現代の視覚の枠組みを使ってきたとしたら
Let's see what people and the world say
人々や世界が何を言っているか見てみましょう
In fact, the problem of heterosexual Chinese
実は中国人異性愛者問題
Putting back the architecture of the modern sight where the grammar resides
文法が存在する現代の光景のアーキテクチャを取り戻す
You will find that heterosexuality is definitely not just a language problem
多異性愛は間違いなく言語の問題だけではないことがわかるでしょう
It's not just a matter of language
言語だけの問題ではない
It is more a question of how modern
むしろ問題はいかに現代的かということだ
From the point of view of modernity
現代性の観点から
We found that there are many
たくさんあることが分かりました
Especially since the so-called scientific enlightenment, rationalism
特にいわゆる科学の啓蒙、合理主義以降、
We will emphasize that we are going to modern
私たちは現代に向かっていることを強調します。
We are going to mechanize
機械化していきます
This seems to be a very progressive orientation
これは非常に進歩的な方向性だと思われます
But if you look at the original culture
しかし、元の文化を見てみると、
grammatical rhetoric down to these discussions of polysexuality
多性愛に関する議論に至るまでの文法レトリック
you will find
見つけるだろう
It turns out that in the language revolution of Chinese
中国語の言語革命では、
Has a flipped modern angle
反転したモダンな角度を持っています
Inside this angle that flips modern events
現代の出来事をひっくり返すこの角度の内側
it provides another mode of feeling
それは別の感情モードを提供します
or another affective construct
または別の感情構造
for example
例えば
We're about to talk about Zhu Zhiqing
朱志青について話しましょう
Zhu Zhiqing says
朱志青氏は言う
we really need a new language
新しい言語が必要です
So where do we start with this new language?
では、この新しい言語をどこから始めればよいのでしょうか?
Zhu Zhiqing is also I.A. Richard
朱志青もI.A.リチャードです
Colleagues who were teaching in China at the time
当時中国で教えていた同僚たち
He is from the Department of Chinese and Richard is from the Department of Foreign Languages.
彼は中国語学科の出身で、リチャードは外国語学部の出身です。
So Zhu Zhiqing once wrote an article called
そこで朱志青はかつて次のような記事を書いた。
Versatile examples
多彩な例
I guess it has something to do with the influence of I.A. Richard
I.A.リチャードの影響が関係しているのではないかと思います。
he just said
彼はちょうど言った
In one of his articles he talked about
彼の記事の一つで彼はこう話しました
Europeanization of Chinese language and grammar or new ideas
中国語と文法のヨーロッパ化または新しいアイデア
What kind of connection should we have with each other?
私たちはお互いにどのようなつながりを持つべきでしょうか？
Finally, there is a very simple conclusion that
最後に、非常にシンプルな結論が得られます。
The biggest difference between Chinese and Western poetry
中国の詩と西洋の詩の最大の違い
not in grammar at all
文法が全く通じない
Thinking and Feeling Patterns
思考と感情のパターン
He said the new sensory style of Chinese poetry
彼は中国の詩の新しい感覚のスタイルについて言いました
must be fresh
新鮮でなければなりません
metaphor hint contrast
比喩のヒントのコントラスト
This is the key to the development of Chinese
これが中国語発展の鍵です
He does not deny that grammar is necessary
彼は文法が必要であることを否定していない
but he thinks
しかし彼は考えます
There must be metaphors, hints, contrasts
比喩、ヒント、対比が必要です
this concise
この簡潔な
even a bit economical syntax
少しでも経済的な構文
to write poetry
詩を書く
Then such a new poem
そうすると、こんな新しい詩が
Only then can it lead to more rich meanings
そうして初めて、より豊かな意味が生まれるのです
should we
我々がすべき
Everyone knows that Zhu Zhiqing's prose is very famous
朱志青の散文が有名であることは誰もが知っています
Then let's take a look at a poem by Zhu Zhiqing
それでは、朱志青の詩を見てみましょう。
okay
わかった
this very long poem
このとても長い詩
I only cited one of them
そのうちの1つだけ引用しました
He said like evil beasts
彼は邪悪な獣のように言った
Instinctively feel like some blood and flesh
本能的に血と肉のような感覚を感じる
They also seem to be driven by something
彼らも何かに突き動かされているようだ
Think of these dull copper plates
この鈍い銅板のことを考えてください
Bai Liang's role
バイリャンの役割
In their eyes, the warehouse is crowded and piled up
彼らの目には倉庫が混雑して積み上げられているように見えます
It's these homologs and toes
それはこれらのホモログとつま先です
It's just a doll
ただの人形だよ
from everything in kokura
小倉のすべてから
I got to know each other quietly like this
こうして静かに知り合った
That self-authored Xi Si is modern
自著の西思は現代的だ
this is very clear
これは非常に明らかです
he talks about capitalism
彼は資本主義について話します
There are three sources of economic modernity
経済的近代性の源は 3 つある
The first source is capitalism
第一の根源は資本主義
So if a man becomes a beast
それで人間が獣になったら
just a decorative figure
ただの飾りフィギュア
is this the modern we want
これが我々が望む現代なのか
In Zhu Zhiqing's "Modern Times in Xiaocang"
朱志青著『小倉現代』
he shouted like this
彼はこう叫んだ
or question like this
またはこのような質問
Another poem is also modern
もう一つの詩も現代的です
Chi Zhijun's very famous peach-colored cloud
Chi Zhijunの非常に有名な桃色の雲
He said that in the details of Shenxia
彼はシェンシアの詳細でこう言った
from chimney spirit
煙突の精霊から
big peachy cloud
大きな桃色の雲
Made of a beautiful smokeberry
美しいスモークベリーで作られています
transparent peachy cloud
透明な桃色の雲
the last paragraph he said
彼が言った最後の段落
Girls who really create stressful problems
本当にストレスフルな問題を引き起こす女の子たち
The girl from the nose
鼻から出た女の子
when the iron gate poured out
鉄の門から水が流れ出るとき
beautiful peachy clouds
美しい桃色の雲
become in the summer valley
夏の谷になる
brewing madness rainstorm
醸し出す狂気の暴風雨
heavy and terrible dark clouds
重くて恐ろしい暗雲
you know the original one
オリジナルのものを知っていますか
Peach-colored clouds made of smoke mold
煙カビで作った桃色の雲
about industrial development
産業発展について
But why does industrial development
しかし、なぜ産業が発展するのか
Feminines from that
そこからのフェミニンさ
After coming out of the narrow iron gate
狭い鉄門を出ると
will become a rainstorm
暴風雨になるだろう
What about the heavy, terrible dark clouds?
重くて恐ろしい暗雲はどうですか？
you know here is talking
ここで話しているのは知っていますか
possible industrial development
産業発展の可能性
significant impact on people
人々に重大な影響を与える
so it's economical
だから経済的です
Now a very important source in my heart
今では私の心の中の大切な情報源となっています
industrial development
産業開発
third Feimin
3番目のフェイミン
That was the famous
あれが有名だった
Another Poet Feng Wenbing's Street
もう一つの詩人、馮文冰の街
he himself said
彼自身が言いました
He later wrote this
彼は後にこう書きました
flash text said
フラッシュテキストが言った
I myself walked to Wangfujing Street
私も王府井街まで歩いて行きました
Standing on the street and seeing these scenes
路上に立ってこの光景を見て
He said that there is no car pool on the street
彼は、路上に駐車場はないと言った
no oil barrel is lonely
孤独な石油樽はない
oil drum P.O.
オイルドラム私書箱
come to pray
祈りに来てください
Throw away the car's code X
車のコードXを捨ててください
How can Arabic numerals be lonely?
アラビア数字ってどうして寂しいのでしょうか？
car lonely
車が寂しい
lonely street
寂しい通り
human loneliness
人間の孤独
this song is very simple
この曲はとてもシンプルです
corpses are called streets
死体はストリートと呼ばれる
He said I just stood on the street and saw
彼は私が通りに立って見ただけだと言いました
But you will find that he is lonely again and again
でもあなたは彼が何度も孤独であることに気づくだろう
It is no longer in Chinese
もう中国語ではない
lonely sandbar cold
孤独な砂州の寒さ
Or the loneliness is as deep as the loneliness of autumn
あるいは孤独は秋の孤独のように深い
The loneliness that I understand is not
私が理解できる孤独は
On the contrary, there is a distance between things and me
逆に物と私の間には距離がある
The more objective I am, the more subjective I am
客観的であればあるほど主観的になる
The more I get separated from you, the new loneliness
君から離れれば離れるほど新たな孤独が生まれる
And what is this loneliness talking about
そしてこの孤独は何を語っているのでしょうか
is city life
都会の生活です
This is also an important source of economic modernity
これは経済の近代性の重要な源泉でもあります
So let's take a simple example with three hands
それでは、3 つの手を使った簡単な例を見てみましょう
Discover how Chinese is modern
中国語がいかに現代的であるかを知る
In fact, Chinese poets are pioneers
実際、中国の詩人は先駆者です
He does a lot of work that looks like alchemy
彼は錬金術のような仕事をたくさんしている
Through these poems we
これらの詩を通して私たちは
Chinese poets can be seen
中国の詩人も見られる
how
どうやって
Facing the modern times, attempting to enter the modern times
現代と向き合い、現代に入ろうとする
And how to brew a new modernity while wandering
そして放浪しながら新たな現代性を醸成する方法
Finally I want to ask the question at the beginning
最後に冒頭の質問をさせていただきたいと思います
maybe we don't have the answer
もしかしたら私たちには答えがないかもしれない
But through these arguments
しかし、これらの議論を通じて
Maybe we can have a preliminary solution
暫定的な解決策が見つかるかも知れません
After the whole discussion, you will find that
議論全体を終えると、次のことがわかります。
The Pull Moment Between Precision and Multi-Benefit
精度とマルチベネフィットの間の瞬間
Perhaps the first of these we can say
おそらくこれらの中で最初に言えることは、
Language is not just a tool
言語は単なるツールではありません
It is an organ that shapes the inner mind
内なる心を形作る器官です
So you see so many commentators
非常に多くのコメンテーターがいます
how they use language to establish themselves
彼らは自分自身を確立するために言語をどのように使用するか
Understand what others drive their ideas
他の人が自分のアイデアをどのように推進しているかを理解する
Language is definitely not just on the truck
言語はトラックに乗っているだけではありません
the second
二番目
We need the language of logical cognition
論理的認識の言語が必要です
It is also necessary to seek a language for cross-domain co-editing
クロスドメイン共同編集のための言語を探すことも必要
Cross-domain co-reform We have been talking about cross-domain
クロスドメインの共同改革 私たちはクロスドメインについて話してきました。
cross field
クロスフィールド
in the interdisciplinary process
学際的なプロセスの中で
how do we express
どのように表現しますか
How do we properly understand others
他人を正しく理解するにはどうすればよいですか
and the ability to incorporate new sympathies
新しい共感を取り入れる能力
I think language also needs empathy
言語にも共感が必要だと思う
not just cognition
認知だけではなく
third point
3番目のポイント
From this discourse
この談話から
We can see that language is constantly in transition
言語は常に変遷していることが分かります
and different cultures
そして異文化
From the process of handover and reflection
引き継ぎと反映の過程から
It is ancient and modern, China and the West borrow from each other
古代と現代、中国と西洋が相互に借用している
Mutual construction and handover of cross-border civilizational achievements
国境を越えた文明成果の相互建設と継承
So what we call Chinese now
つまり、今私たちが中国語と呼んでいるものは、
not only belong to a certain era
特定の時代に属しているだけではなく
a political entity
政治的実体
only a certain generation
ある世代だけ
It actually keeps us in the process of transformation
それは実際に私たちを変革の過程に留まらせます
This is the real development of language
これが言語の本当の発達です
The development of Chinese language will not only be in China
中国語の発展は中国だけではない
If you notice that Japan, South Korea, and Vietnam
気がつけば日本、韓国、ベトナム
should be an important one
重要なものであるはずです
We can even say that it is another
それは別のものであるとさえ言えます
The scope of the study of modernity
近代研究の範囲
part in japanese
日本語の部分
like professor kim munjin
像金文津教授
He put his own Japanese
彼は自分の日本語を載せた
translate into chinese
中国語に翻訳する
It is about the relationship between Chinese and the East Asian world
それは中国と東アジア世界との関係についてです
Speaking of Japan and South Korea
日本と韓国といえば
how to use your own way
自分なりの使い方
to interpret classical Chinese
古典中国語を解釈する
For example, reverse word order
たとえば語順を逆にする
add some special symbols
いくつかの特殊な記号を追加する
So he doesn't just have one transformation
つまり、彼の変身は1つだけではありません
There is not only one way to face modern times
現代と向き合う方法は一つだけではない
I think what I offer today is
今日私が提案するのは、
China
中国
How to build through the mutual construction of China and the West
中国と西側の相互建設を通じてどのように構築するか
to achieve
達成する
not to say that achieved
達成したとは言えません
To continue to promote the transformation of Chinese
中国人の変革を推進し続ける
report here today
今日ここで報告します
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました